<?xml version="1.1" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<databaseChangeLog xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
                   xmlns="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog"
                   xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog
                   http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-3.6.xsd">

    <changeSet author="Oleksandr Khomenko" id="v-0.0.1_002_000001" runOnChange="true">
        <insert tableName="product_categories">
            <column name="id">1</column>
            <column name="name">Fruits</column>
            <column name="description">
                Fruits are the means by which angiosperms disseminate seeds.
                Edible fruits, in particular, have propagated with the movements of humans
                and animals in a symbiotic relationship as a means for seed dispersal
                and nutrition; in fact, humans and many animals have become dependent
                on fruits as a source of food. Accordingly, fruits account for a substantial
                fraction of the world's agricultural output, and some (such as the apple
                and the pomegranate) have acquired extensive cultural and symbolic meanings.
            </column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="product_categories">
            <column name="id">2</column>
            <column name="name">Vegetables</column>
            <column name="description">
                In everyday usage, vegetables are certain parts of plants that are consumed
                by humans as food as part of a savory meal. Originally, the traditional
                term (still commonly used in biology) included the flowers, fruit, stems,
                leaves, roots, tubers, bark, seeds, and all other plant matter, although
                modern-day culinary usage of the term vegetable may exclude food derived
                from plants such as fruits, nuts, and cereal grains, but include seeds such
                as pulses; the term vegetable is somewhat arbitrary, and can be largely
                defined through culinary and cultural tradition.
            </column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="product_categories">
            <column name="id">3</column>
            <column name="name">Spices</column>
            <column name="description">
                A spice is a seed, fruit, root, bark, or other plant substance primarily
                used for flavoring, coloring or preserving food. Spices are distinguished
                from herbs, which are the leaves, flowers, or stems of plants used for
                flavoring or as a garnish. Many spices have antimicrobial properties.
                This may explain why spices are more commonly used in warmer climates,
                which have more infectious diseases, and why the use of spices is prominent
                in meat, which is particularly susceptible to spoiling. Spices are
                sometimes used in medicine, religious rituals, cosmetics or perfume
                production, or as a vegetable.
            </column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="product_categories">
            <column name="id">4</column>
            <column name="name">Sausages</column>
            <column name="description">
                A sausage is a cylindrical meat product usually made from ground meat,
                often pork, beef, or veal, along with salt, spices and other flavourings,
                and breadcrumbs, encased by a skin. Typically, a sausage is formed
                in a casing traditionally made from intestine, but sometimes from synthetic
                materials. Sausages that are sold raw are cooked in many ways, including
                pan-frying, broiling and barbecuing. Some sausages are cooked during
                processing and the casing may then be removed.
            </column>
        </insert>
    </changeSet>

    <changeSet author="Oleksandr Khomenko" id="v-0.0.1_002_000002" runOnChange="true">
        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Apple</column>
            <column name="description">
                An apple is a sweet, edible fruit produced by an apple tree (Malus pumila).
                Apple trees are cultivated worldwide as a fruit tree, and is the most
                widely grown species in the genus Malus. The tree originated in Central
                Asia, where its wild ancestor, Malus sieversii, is still found today.
                Apples have been grown for thousands of years in Asia and Europe, and
                were brought to North America by European colonists. Apples have religious
                and mythological significance in many cultures, including Norse, Greek
                and European Christian traditions.
            </column>
            <column name="price">12.99</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">1</column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Orange</column>
            <column name="description">
                The orange is the fruit of the citrus species Citrus × sinensis in
                the family Rutaceae. It is also called sweet orange, to distinguish
                it from the related Citrus × aurantium, referred to as bitter orange.
                The sweet orange reproduces asexually (apomixis through nucellar embryony);
                varieties of sweet orange arise through mutations.
            </column>
            <column name="price">10.87</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">1</column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Papaya</column>
            <column name="description">
                The papaya (from Carib via Spanish), papaw, or pawpaw is the plant Carica papaya,
                one of the 22 accepted species in the genus Carica of the family Caricaceae.
                Its origin is in the tropics of the Americas, perhaps from southern Mexico
                and neighboring Central America.
            </column>
            <column name="price">39.78</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">1</column>
        </insert>

        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Potato</column>
            <column name="description">
                The potato is a starchy, tuberous crop from the perennial nightshade
                Solanum tuberosum. Potato may be applied to both the plant and the
                edible tuber. Potato has become a staple food in many parts of
                the world and an integral part of much of the world's food supply.
                It is the world's fourth-largest food crop, following maize, wheat,
                and rice. The green leaves and green skins of tubers exposed
                to the light are toxic.
            </column>
            <column name="price">2.99</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">2</column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Onion</column>
            <column name="description">
                The onion (Allium cepa L., from Latin cepa "onion"), also known
                as the bulb onion or common onion, is a vegetable that is
                the most widely cultivated species of the genus Allium.
                Its close relatives include the garlic, shallot, leek,
                chive, and Chinese onion.
            </column>
            <column name="price">1.59</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">2</column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Cucumber</column>
            <column name="description">
                Cucumber (Cucumis sativus) is a widely cultivated plant
                in the gourd family, Cucurbitaceae. It is a creeping
                vine that bears cucumiform fruits that are used
                as vegetables. There are three main varieties of
                cucumber: slicing, pickling, and seedless.
                Within these varieties, several cultivars have
                been created. In North America, the term "wild cucumber"
                refers to plants in the genera Echinocystis and Marah,
                but these are not closely related. The cucumber is originally
                from South Asia, but now grows on most continents. Many different
                types of cucumber are traded on the global market.
            </column>
            <column name="price">2.19</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">2</column>
        </insert>

        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Cinnamon</column>
            <column name="description">
                Cinnamon (/ˈsɪnəmən/ SIN-ə-mən) is a spice obtained from the inner
                bark of several tree species from the genus Cinnamomum. Cinnamon
                is used mainly as an aromatic condiment and flavoring additive
                in a wide variety of cuisines, sweet and savoury dishes, breakfast
                cereals, snackfoods, and traditional foods. The aroma and flavor
                of cinnamon derive from its essential oil and principal component,
                cinnamaldehyde, as well as numerous other constituents, including eugenol.
            </column>
            <column name="price">29.32</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">3</column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Basil</column>
            <column name="description">
                Basil UK: /ˈbæzəl/; US: /ˈbeɪzəl/ (Ocimum basilicum),
                also called great basil or Saint-Joseph's-wort, is a culinary
                herb of the family Lamiaceae (mints). The name "basil" comes
                from Latin, Basilius, and Greek βασιλικόν φυτόν (basilikón phutón),
                "royal/kingly plant".
            </column>
            <column name="price">39.99</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">3</column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Oregano</column>
            <column name="description">
                Oregano (US: /ɔːˈrɛɡənoʊ/ or /əˈrɛɡənoʊ/; UK: /ˌɒrɪˈɡɑːnoʊ/;
                Origanum vulgare) is a flowering plant in the mint family (Lamiaceae).
                It is native to temperate Western and Southwestern Eurasia
                and the Mediterranean region.
            </column>
            <column name="price">37.99</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">3</column>
        </insert>

        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Salami</column>
            <column name="description">
                Salami is a type of cured sausage consisting of fermented and air-dried meat,
                typically beef or pork. Historically, salami was popular among southern
                and central European peasants because it stores at room temperature
                for up to 40 days once cut, supplementing a potentially meager
                or inconsistent supply of fresh meat. Countries and regions across
                Europe make their own traditional varieties of salami.
            </column>
            <column name="price">129.78</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">4</column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Blood sausage</column>
            <column name="description">
                Blood sausages are sausages filled with blood that are cooked
                or dried and mixed with a filler until they are thick enough
                to solidify when cooled. Variants are found worldwide.
                Pig, cattle, sheep, duck, and goat blood can be used, varying by country.
            </column>
            <column name="price">99.99</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">4</column>
        </insert>
        <insert tableName="products">
            <column name="name">Liver sausage</column>
            <column name="description">
                The word liverwurst is an anglicization of German Leberwurst,
                meaning "liver sausage". It is also known as liver sausage by some
                English speakers. It is a sausage eaten in North America, in large
                parts of Europe, including Austria, Bulgaria, Croatia,
                the Czech Republic, Denmark, Finland, Germany, Hungary, the Netherlands,
                Norway, Poland, Romania (especially in Transylvania), Russia, Serbia,
                Slovakia, Slovenia, Sweden, Ukraine, United Kingdom, and
                in South American countries such as Argentina.
            </column>
            <column name="price">78.48</column>
            <column name="product_category_id">4</column>
        </insert>
    </changeSet>
</databaseChangeLog>
